<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Chris Stott</title>
  <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/"/>
  <updated>2011-09-03T00:24:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Stott</name>
    
      <email>chris@chrisstott.ca</email>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Back (Yet) Again</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Back-Yet-Again/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Back-Yet-Again</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Back (Yet) Again&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it pays to get distracted by other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My previous iteration of this site relied on a base &lt;a href=&quot;www.jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; install with a number of add-ons, extensions and hacks to add all of the functionality I wanted. Most of it was working when &lt;a href=&quot;www.octopress.org&quot;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; version 2.0 was announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Octopress 2.0 addressed all of my needs (and the remaining issues) and provided the necessary information to quickly get a site up and running. A quick Google search for running Jekyll under &lt;a href=&quot;www.heroku.com&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; and I was able to get a working site up and running in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have a working &lt;a href=&quot;www.git-scm.com&quot;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; repository, a synchronized &lt;a href=&quot;www.github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; repository and a local copy managed through &lt;a href=&quot;www.dropbox.com&quot;&gt;dropbox&lt;/a&gt;. I like this solution as it is very easy to maintain (i.e., all I need to do is write articles, sync with git and then push it to heroku).  Any patches/changes coming out of Jekyll will be applied to Octopress and can easily be upgraded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I would like to do, besides write in my blog, is change the default layout. Octopress has a nice layout etc. that works in most browsers (i.e., mobile, iPad and PC). The colour scheme etc. is a little dark for my liking. In the spirit of &quot;shipping&quot; I'm going to keep writing and modify the layout when I have time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Back Again</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Back-Again/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Back-Again</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well I'm back again. Ironically in the past when I've stopped blogging
in the past it was usually because I got distracted by some
technical / business. This time I have a valid reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I added a new team member to my team at work. The individual
who joined was quite keen and interested in personal productivity,
entreprenuerism, etc. I started off with my usual orientation including
directing him to links to things that would support his style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a month or so he asked me if I'd be interested in starting a blog
to capture these great articles. The result is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehabitofthinking.com&quot;&gt;The Habit of Thinking&lt;/a&gt;.
He came up with the great name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So far we've had 2 articles a day for the last month. Basically as I
read my usual information feeds, documents, books, etc. I keep an eye
out for things I think will be relevant. When I see it I add it to a
draft &quot;queue&quot;. Harry then reviews and approves mine. It is pretty neat
as we've been able to keep a growing queue in place so there is usually
a week's worth of entries ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest it has been a bit of a thrill. We got our first follower a
while a go and now we have 4. We are no A-list blogger but we are having
fun (and learning something along the way). All the things I've done to
set up the site improve my skills to work on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll probably be referencing articles across the sites. This site will
contain my more detailed articles (i.e., long ones) and the other will
be more short snippets of information or links to longer articles.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ruby Koans</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Ruby-Koans/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Ruby-Koans</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To help me learn my current &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;blogging tool&lt;/a&gt; I have started to teach myself
Ruby.  Ironically it is the same way that I taught myself to program in C many years ago (20+).
Back then the &quot;Interwebs&quot; were in their infancy and I wanted to learn C.  I didn't have a book
so I searched around the system and found the &quot;learnc&quot; tutorial that was built in to Unix.
Basically I'd start it up, look at the examples, and then try to hack the code. I'd figured out
how it was comparing my answer to the systems so I reverse engineered my way to an explanation.
Worked wonders when I got stuck. In the end I was known as quite the C 'hacker' (something that I
was called - not a label I gave myself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway back to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rubykoans.com&quot;&gt;Ruby Koans&lt;/a&gt;. Basically you download them from the
website, make sure you have a good editor (I'm really liking &lt;a href=&quot;http://macvim.org/&quot;&gt;MacVim&lt;/a&gt; and
run the &quot;rake&quot; command. Through a Test Driven Development approach (i.e., Red, Green, Refactor)
you basically work through a series of 274 tests. Each one builds on previous exercises. There
are a couple of hard ones but thanks to google I've been able to look up syntax and guestimate what the
language is doing. There is enough there that you get a pretty good feel for the language. I'm
in no way a Ruby ninja now but I feel I can read &quot;good&quot; Ruby code and get the general gist of what it is doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of &lt;strong&gt;fun&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thinking About Next Steps</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Next-Steps/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Next-Steps</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last little while I've been reflecting what the next steps for
me would be. Some people are motivated to &quot;survive&quot; work so they can
enjoy their passion - usually something outside of the job. Others are
mindlessly working day after day just to make ends meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me that isn't living. I'm driven to make a difference. I've been
asked why can't I just keep my head down and do a good &quot;enough&quot; job.
I've been told to enter an organization and &quot;sit on my hands&quot; so that I
didn't disturb anyone. WFT?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's not making things better. That's not growth. If you are not
moving forward you are slowly dying - and that's the last thing I want
to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I've learned lots about effectively running
organizations. I've proven time and time again that I can deliver the
&quot;&lt;em&gt;impossible projects&lt;/em&gt;&quot;. The challenge I've had is that most companies
only have the endurance to conduct change like these (and usually it is
massive change) very infrequently. Once I've delivered the project they
don't know what to do with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I belive that any impossible project is delivered by a team.
My skill, and gift, is the ability to get the best out of a team.
Ultimately my goal is to have them deliver successfully and at the end
of the day have them look back and say &quot;look what we did!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there organizations that are willing to leverage my skills? Do I
need to create an organization that is open to shifting and changing to
the market so that &lt;strong&gt;we&lt;/strong&gt; can make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Making a Difference</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Making-A-Difference/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Making-A-Difference</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following my attendance at the DemoCamp I’ve been thinking a lot about what I could offer a start up.
I’m definitely interested in figuring out how I can help startups. Part of me wished that I was a kick-ass
coder again but I'm starting to realize that given my almost 20 years of “learning” my bigger offering
would be my business knowledge. I've read hundreds of business books, articles, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many who read this type of information I have spend most of my career trying to apply it. The
information just just clicks with me. My challenge is that it has taken me all these years to realize
that I'm probably better suited for an entrepreneurial venture than being a drone in a large organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is all about contribution.  As with most organizations the challenge is that if you don’t play the
political games after a time everyone’s skills depreciates.  There might be individuals with much more
to contribute but they are usually limited by what they are “allowed to do” - and that is limited by
what their boss feels comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>DemoCamp19</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/DemoCamp19/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/DemoCamp19</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I went &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; outside of my usual box. A few weeks ago I found a local website that was
advertising a local Demo Camp event for the Calgary area. I thought &quot;What the heck?&quot; so I made arrangements
to head down and attend the meeting. Despite being a very strong &lt;strong&gt;INTJ&lt;/strong&gt; I headed down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a good time. I ran in to the lady who used to do the role I'm currently performing. She has
really branched out and has developed a successful career as a leadership coach. We had a good chat
catching up and then she gave me some tips on the meeting format, what was usually discussed and some
other local meetings that might be interesting. Thanks for letting me tag along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In talking with her and others there you could feel a real 'joy' around what people were working on.
Some were small personal projects and others larger platform based initiatives. I still need to figure
out how to introduce myself. Corporate IT guy comes across awkward when I'm talking to a 22 year-old
entrepreneur who would probably rather work at McDonalds then do what I do. In any case, I feel I have
skills I could offer them. Ah, the joys of &lt;strike&gt;age&lt;/strike&gt; maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm looking forward to the next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Learning New Things</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Learning-New-Things/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Learning-New-Things</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I discovered a really interesting site a few weeks ago. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.p2pu.org/&quot;&gt;P2PU&lt;/a&gt; is looking to
create an educational revolution. In their words:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Peer 2 Peer University (P2PU) is an online community of open study groups for short university-level courses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I went to our local &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.calgaryagile.com/&quot;&gt;Agile Users Group&lt;/a&gt; meeting. I try to
get out when they have an interesting topic. Tonight it was on Ruby on Rails. It was just basic
introduction to the language and but it gave me the kick in the butt to try one of the P2PU course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've applied for the &quot;Introduction to Ruby and Rails&quot; course. One of the requirements to apply was
to write a chunk of code, in your language of choice, that reads in a sentence and then prints the
words in the sentence in the opposite order. Basic stuff but it was a little challenging given I don't
know Ruby. Thinking up a solution was easy given the trivial nature of the problem so I thought I'd
give it a shot in Ruby using an introductory book provided in the install environment. Once I was
done an hour later I looked at my code and it looked a lot like C - makes sense given that was my
last development language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, whether I get in or not, I think I'm going to investigate Rails some more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Having Fun Again</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Having-Fun-Again/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Having-Fun-Again</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Work was stressful this week. To get my mind off of it I spent part of today playing around with Jekyll,
HTML5 Boilerplate and Compass. It was very satisfying making a working system out of a number of tools
I haven't really used before. I knew what I wanted and was able to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on all of this makes me realize that there are lots of smart people on the web. The tools
I'm using are well thought out and designed. With little more than a hacker attitude (i.e., curiosity,
willingness to make mistakes, eagerness to learn, etc.) I've been able to quickly get up to speed and
become productive using several tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Research Bug Strikes Again!</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/The-Research-Bug/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/The-Research-Bug</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Even thought I had a workable solution, after doing some more reading (primarily on big name
developers websites) I noticed that a number of them were either using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wordpress.org&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moveabletype.org&quot;&gt;Moveable Type&lt;/a&gt; or they were opting for simpler solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've always preferred &quot;simple&quot; to complex so I had a look at the solutions they were implementing.
Some of them were really neat. The ones that attracted me were the sites that relied on a basic markup
language and static webpages. I think it is the developer in me that drew me to these solutions. I used
to enjoy hacking away code in emacs using scripts/macro languages/#defines/etc. to create nice tight chunks of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind I didn't want to spend months doing research I limited my analysis to two tools:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://nanoc.stoneship.org/&quot;&gt;Nanok v3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Both of these are Ruby
solutions. I've been interested in learning Ruby so I thought I would have a look at these to see if
they would teach me a thing or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending a few days playing with each and eventually settled on Jekyll. I've also started to
use &lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gitx.frim.nl/&quot;&gt;GitX&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://macvim.org/&quot;&gt;MacVim&lt;/a&gt;. All very cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basics of the site have been set up. Now I just need to use the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://html5boilerplate.com/&quot;&gt;HTML5 Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to make it look reasonable and I've got my platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Damn, that was easy!</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/That-was-Easy/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/That-was-Easy</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I remember starting the whole “I need a blog” thing. I spent &lt;strike&gt;days&lt;/strike&gt;, &lt;strike&gt;no weeks&lt;/strike&gt;,
no months reading numerous HTML/CSS coding books with the hope of becoming a coding expert before I put anything
“out there”. Of course that required full analysis of all the hosting options, languages (PHP, Perl, Ruby, etc.)
before I could pick a tool. I’d have to pay for hosting and then spend a considerable amount of time developing my
blog layout - all before I could add content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now look at me. Find URL - check. Look at hosting options - check. Curious about Tumblr and Posterious. Can they
support personal URLs?? Test out with tumblr and BANG I’ve got a customized blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn, that was easy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Start of the Journey</title>
    <link href="http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Start-of-the-Journey/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ChrisStott.ca/blog/Start-of-the-Journey</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in the tech business for almost 20 years. Over that time I have worked on just about all
“sides” of the table. I’ve been a management consultant, an employee, an independent contractor, a
consultant working for a &lt;strike&gt;pimping&lt;/strike&gt; consulting agency. My specialty has primarily been
in the technology area, however, I’ve been “accused” (not sure if that is a bad thing) of being a
people geek, process geek, etc. Reality is I’m just a geek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being rewarded well for all this work (for the most part) I’ve always been restless. I’m
always looking for the next big challenge. Once I get a project, group, or department running smoothly
I get bored. I start to look for the next challenge, even if that means improving upon the model we
just put in place. I live for that but unfortunately not everyone is the same. Some suffer from change
fatigue while others are just waiting for a quiet moment to climb back in to the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I’ve become a “suit” - someone who is comfortable standing up in front a crowded room, taking
the lead and communicating the direction and vision of very large projects. But part of me is also a
hacker. Not in the “black hat/grey hat/white hat” way but more of a curious person whose not afraid
to take apart problems. The bugger the challenge the bigger the curiosity. I get sucked in by that
curiosity until I resolve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started numerous blogs but I feel like this one is different. The purpose is to help me figure
out the journey I’m on and figure out where I want to end up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
